Contact

mrsmyrtleroy1@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mrsmyrtleroy (LinkedIn) www.kp.org (Company)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Healthcare Information Technology Leadership

Languages

Tagalog (Professional Working)
English (Full Professional)
Spanish (Limited Working)

Certifications

Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP) Project 2010
Healthcare IT Technician

Project Management Professional

Fundamentals of Critical Care Support

ITIL v3 Foundations

Myrtle Roy

Kaiser Permanente Clinical Operations Manager Urgent Care/ Clinical Decision Unit BSN, MBA, PMP

Mclean, Virginia

Summary

Experienced Senior Leader in healthcare with 18+ years of professional experience in multiple industries. Emergency room trauma / lead nurse with experience in logistics, resource, change, process, and personnel management. Utilize analytical and intuitive skills to assess and effectively manage operations, projects, protocols, and strategies. Positive, results-oriented communication style and ability to build strong relationships, both patient and professional, that consistently provides exceptional quality healthcare management. Clinical instruction and supervision experience demonstrating commitment to quality patient care and satisfaction through service and client relationship management as well as contributing to the nursing community. Experience with Department of Defense policies and processes; Information Security and Information Assurance, ensuring system security and data integrity. Commitment to exceptional customer service and satisfaction through client relationship development with program stakeholders as well as executive leadership. With a continued desire for self-improvement; my focus, commitment and organization facilitate results that exceed expectations.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS AND EXPERTISE

- Licensed Registered Nurse State of DC, NV, VA
- Project Management Professional (PMP)
- Foundations of Critical Care Support Certified
- ACLS Certified through 2018
- PALS Certified through 2018
- Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP) Project 2010
- CompTIA Healthcare IT Technician Certification
- Cerner PowerChart / Rumba (7+ yrs)
- T-System / Meditech / PICIS (2+ yrs)
- EPIC Healthcare Systems (5+ yrs)
- HIPAA / HITECH / DICOM Policies

ITIL V3 Foundations

Experience

Kaiser Permanente

6 years 11 months

Clinical Operations Manager Tysons Corner Urgent Care/ Clinical Decision Unit

April 2015 - Present (5 years 4 months)

Mclean, Virginia

- •Met annual budget by 10% improving supply management and decreasing cost through improved utilization management
- •Achieved 80% reduction in overtime expenses through effective management of staff and increased new hires
- •Manage daily clinical operations, 85 staff schedules and effective staff utilization to support delivery of quality care
- •Address daily patient concerns, complaints and implement service recovery in order to deliver exceptional experience
- •Manage quality improvement initiatives and ensures compliance with HEDIS indicators and mandated standards
- •Streamlined department operations increasing patient turnover and treating approximately 80,000 patients annually
- •Establish performance goals and provide coaching, feedback, and career development for up to 40 direct reports
- •Collaborate with ancillary departments to decrease treatment time, decreasing overall visit patient length of stay
- •Responsible for accurate documentation on QA reports, performance evaluations, payroll, and budget variance reports
- •Collaborate with Human Resources to recruit and hire staff; coordinate orientation, and on-board new staff members
- •Collaborate with physicians to coordinate day-to-day patient care and ensure timely appointment access for patients

Mid Atlantic States Regional Clinical Educator Urgent Care September 2013 - April 2015 (1 year 8 months) Regional

- •Within first 60 days, reduced annual internal training costs by \$10k by leveraging vendor
- •Provided skills based training for RNs, LPNs, and Urgent Care Techs in eleven Urgent Cares

- •Assisted department managers in identifying educational needs and coordination of training
- •Participated on interdisciplinary committees to coordinate training for upcoming initiatives
- •Managed clinical portion of employee orientation and ongoing department specific competencies
- •Analyzed workflow and nursing practice/ processes for improvement and recommendations
- •Developed multiple educational curricula to increase and maximize clinical staff competencies
- •2014 Kaiser Permanente Mid-Atlantic States Golden Apple Award recipient for Excellence in Education

Cybaris Consulting, LLC Chief Operations Officer December 2010 - October 2013 (2 years 11 months)

- •Provided Project Management services managing organizational and operational restructuring
- •Provided monthly project status corporate briefings to executive, marketing & operations teams
- •Developed dynamic Concept of Operations or System Design Document, creating new capabilities
- •Managed day-to-day operations centered on maintaining high levels of availability and consistency
- •Managed executive goals through daily operations complying with legal and financial regulations
- •Managed operational budget of \$500,000 encompassing marketing, operations, long term assets
- •Established objectives, allocate resources, and budget to support strategic business objectives
- •Established operational processes and industry best practices through process engineering
- •Processed potential RFP's, RFI's, RFQ's--process quotes, negotiate sale conditions & rates
- •Built business relationships to capture agency pain points to support client missions

Inova Fairfax Regional Trauma Center Staff ER Registered Nurse, Emergency Dept Level 1 Trauma Center January 2011 - August 2013 (2 years 8 months)

Fairfax, Virginia

- •Supervised up to 15 nursing personnel to deliver quality care in fast paced environment
- •Effectively managed healthcare personnel to facilitate patient flow decreasing length of stay
- •Developed preceptor program reducing preceptor time by 40%, increasing patient visits by 10%
- •Displayed innovative thinking to adapt quickly to situational variables improving patient outcomes
- •Displayed clinical excellence in fast paced environment treating up to 110K patients annually
- •Analyzed patients' clinical data making appropriate recommendations to improve patient care
- •Coordinated with numerous hospital in-patient and out-patient units to improve transfer of care
- •Provided numerous clinical end user feedback during EPIC healthcare system deployment
- •Effectively managed multiple computerized patient charts ensuring compliance with HIPAA/ HITECH

Sunrise Hospital

ER Trauma Nurse

April 2010 - December 2010 (9 months)

- •Participated in multiple nursing committees to improve triage process, decreasing treatment time
- •Communicated chart and peer review feedback ensuring documentation standards compliance
- •Trained nurse apprentice and travel nurses to hospital processes creating patient focused culture
- •Provided recommendations to nursing administration to improve patient flow through

St Rose Dominican Hospital-Siena Campus ER Trauma Nurse March 2008 - December 2010 (2 years 10 months) Henderson, NV

St Rose Dominican Hospital
Team Lead Med/Surg ER Holds
March 2007 - March 2008 (1 year 1 month)

New Mexico Army National Guard, Medical Detachment Officer in Charge, Laboratory Operations November 1999 - October 2007 (8 years)

St. Rose Dominican Hospitals 3 years 4 months

Staff/Charge Nurse for Medical/Surgical Unit January 2006 - March 2007 (1 year 3 months) Henderson, Nevada

Administrative Communications on Medical Surgical Unit December 2003 - January 2006 (2 years 2 months) Henderson, Nevada

Nurse Apprentice for Medical/Surgical Unit May 2004 - December 2005 (1 year 8 months) Henderson, Nevada

Education

Harvard School of Public Health

Executive and Continuing Professional Education, Health Care Project Management: The Intersection of Strategy, People, and Process

Strategyzer Academy

The Business Model Generation Workshop & Masterclass · (2014 - 2014)

University of Phoenix

Masters in Business Administration, Business (2007 - 2009)

Nevada State College

Bachelors in Science, Nursing · (2003 - 2005)

New Mexico Military Institute

Associates of Arts, Liberal Arts · (1999 - 2001)